<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>African American &amp; African Studies, Minor</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p>African American &amp; African Studies is an interdisciplinary field of study in the humanities, arts, and social sciences. This major introduces students to the social, cultural, historical, and artistic dimensions of global African Diaspora and Black communities in the United States, Africa, Europe, Asia, the Caribbean, Latin America, and Pacific regions of the world. The instructors are creative, accessible and highly qualified, with specializations across a range of disciplines. Students are exposed to and trained to think critically about the conditions and demands of global societies. Students may choose to enrich their education by studying for a summer, a quarter, or a year in Africa, or by studying for a quarter in the Caribbean. Majors and Minors are also encouraged to take advantage of relevant internship opportunities.</p>
<h2>The Program</h2>
<p>The purpose of this program is to give students a sense of the individual characteristics and common concerns of Black communities in Africa, the United States, and the wider Diaspora. The African American emphasis includes courses on history, culture, and the impact of developments in politics and the economy on the social organization of Black people in the United States. The African Diaspora emphasis enables students to study the way Black communities outside Africa and the United States have dealt with questions of race and ethnicity. It also considers how they have defined their identity in the political arena as well, by using religion, theater and dance, literature, and film. The African emphasis allows students to focus on Africa's recent history, social issues, and contemporary culture.</p>
<h3>Career Alternatives</h3>
<p>Students minoring in African American &amp; African Studies gain knowledge, strong critical thinking, and analytical, problem-solving, and communication skills, all suited for advanced studies in the social sciences, law, education, and other professional schools. Graduates in the major have pursued careers in education, the private and public sectors, the non-profit sector, international development agencies, and human service. The interdisciplinary nature of African American &amp; African Studies is excellent preparation for professions in community organizations such as the Urban League, NAACP, and the Office of Economic Opportunity.</p>
<h3>Minor Advisor</h3>
<p><a href="mailto:kampaw@ucdavis.edu">Katherine Ampaw-Matthei, M.Ed.</a>; <a href="https://aas.ucdavis.edu/advising">Advising</a></p>
<h2>American History &amp; Institutions</h2>
<p>This University requirement can be satisfied by completion of <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AAS 010">AAS 010</span></span>, <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AAS 100">AAS 100</span></span>; listed in <a href="/undergraduate-education/university-degree-requirements/american-history-institutions-requirement/">American History &amp; Institutions Requirement</a>.</p>

]]>
</informationtext>
<requirementstext name="Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Although a course may be listed more than once, such a course may satisfy only one requirement.</p>
<table class="sc_courselist">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup>
<col class="codecol"/>
<col class="titlecol"/>
<col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/>
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr class="hidden noscript">
<th scope="col">Code</th>
<th scope="col">Title</th>
<th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="even firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Choose one of the following:</span></td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AAS 010">AAS 010</span></div></td><td>African-American Culture &amp; Society</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AAS 012">AAS 012</span></div></td><td>Introduction to African Studies</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AAS 015">AAS 015</span></div></td><td>Introduction to African American Humanities</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AAS 017">AAS 017</span></div></td><td>Women in African Societies</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AAS 018">AAS 018</span></div></td><td>Introduction to Caribbean Studies</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="AAS 080">AAS 080</span></div></td><td>Introduction to Black Politics</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Select any five upper division courses offered in African American &amp; African Studies.</span></td><td class="hourscol">20</td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent"><a href="/courses-subject-code/aas/">African American &amp; African Studies (AAS) courses.</a></span></div></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="listsum"><td colspan="2">Total Units</td><td class="hourscol">24</td></tr></tbody>
</table>

]]>
</requirementstext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The <span class="title-main">African American &amp; African Studies </span>minor gives students a sense of the individual characteristics and common concerns of black communities in Africa, the United States, and in the wider Diaspora.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

