<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Animal Behavior, Master of Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Group Office</h2>
<p>227A Green<span id="htmldiff0" title="Added content"><span class="diffadded"> Hall, formerly </span></span>Life Sciences; <a href="http://anb.ucdavis.edu/" target="_blank">Animal Behavior Graduate Group;</a> <a href="https://anb.ucdavis.edu/faculty" target="_blank">Faculty</a></p>
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p><strong>The Master of Science degree is offered only en route to the Ph.D.</strong></p>
<p>The Ph.D. program in Animal Behavior is an interdepartmental program focusing on the mechanisms underlying behavior, the evolution of behavior, and the applications of behavior to current problems in conservation biology and animal welfare. The program trains students for teaching and research in a variety of areas, including anthropology, animal science, ecology, entomology, neurobiology, psychology, physiology, veterinary science, wildlife biology, and zoology. Resources available to students, in addition to various departmental facilities, include those of the California National Primate Research Center, Bodega Marine Laboratory, and the UC Natural Reserve System.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/ganb">Animal Behavior</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>Are you interested in understanding the adaptive and evolutionary bases of animal behavior?  Come train for teaching and research in a variety of disciplines, including animal science, anthropology, ecology, entomology, neurobiology, psychology, physiology, veterinary science, wildlife biology, and zoology. Research areas include behavioral ecology and sociobiology, animal communication, animal management and welfare, physiology and behavior, behavior and conservation, primate behavior, modeling of behavior, and behavioral development. The program is structured with core courses and individually tailored studies to provide in-depth knowledge relevant to each student’s interests.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

