<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Applied Mathematics, Master of Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>Students prepare for careers where mathematics is applied to problems in the physical and life sciences, engineering, and management. The degree requirements consist of rigorous training in applied mathematics, including course work and a research dissertation under the direction of a member of the Graduate Group in Applied Mathematics. The M.S. degree provides preparation for further study in applied mathematics or an application area, or for a career in industry or public service. The Ph.D. degree provides preparation for a career in research and/or teaching, or in industrial or national research laboratories. For further information, contact a <span class="diffadded" title="Added content"><a href="mailto:gradadvisor@math.ucdavis.edu">Graduate Advisor</a></span> or 530-754-0823.</p>
<p>New applicants are admitted to the fall quarter only.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>The program admits qualified students with a bachelor's degree in mathematics, physics, chemistry, engineering, economics, the life sciences and related fields. General and Subject GRE scores are required, and applicants should display evidence of strong quantitative skills. Undergraduate courses should include calculus (including vector calculus), linear algebra, and ordinary differential equations. Advanced calculus (introduction to real analysis) is strongly recommended. Additional background in probability, partial differential equations, and/or numerical analysis is a plus. The ability to program in a high-level computer programming language (e.g., C, MATLAB, Python, R, etc.) is assumed.</p>
<h3>Courses</h3>
<p>For a list of the courses in applied mathematics and mathematics, see <a href="/departments-programs-degrees/mathematics/">Mathematics</a>.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gapm">Applied Mathematics</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>Do you want to apply your mathematical ideas to advance the understanding of science and engineering? Students gain advanced knowledge of differential geometry, topology, differential equations, solid and fluid dynamics,  atmospheric sciences, mechanics, optimization &amp; control, theoretical chemistry, computer engineering science, physics, signal/image processing, harmonic analysis, and numerical analysis.  Students graduate with skills necessary for professional research and teaching in applied mathematics.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

