<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Atmospheric Sciences, Doctor of Philosophy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Graduate Group in Atmospheric Sciences offers both M.S. and Ph.D. degree programs. A student may place emphasis on graduate work in one or more of the following fields: air quality meteorology, atmospheric chemistry, cloud physical processes, biometeorology, micrometeorology, numerical weather prediction, remote sensing, climate dynamics, large-scale dynamics, meso-scale and boundary-layer meteorology, computational geosciences, extreme weather, and climate change impacts. The diverse and extensive backgrounds of the faculty allow opportunities for interdisciplinary training and research.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>The Graduate Group in Atmospheric Sciences encourages applications from all interested students with backgrounds in the physical or natural sciences. Basic qualifications for students entering the Atmospheric Sciences graduate program include mathematics to the level of vector calculus and partial differential equations, and one year of college-level physics. Flexibility may be allowed for students with high academic potential, but it is expected that deficiencies in preparatory material and in key undergraduate atmospheric science courses be completed within the first year of graduate study.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gatm">Atmospheric Sciences</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>Weather, it's everywhere! Atmospheric science is the study of the physics, chemistry, and dynamics of the atmosphere and its interrelationship with the hydrosphere and the biosphere. Students gain advanced knowledge of air quality, meteorology, atmospheric chemistry, micrometeorology, biometeorology, climate dynamics, mesoscale meteorology, large-scale dynamics, and numerical weather prediction. </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

