<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Biomedical Engineering, Master of Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Master's Study in Biomedical Engineering</h2>
<p>The Biomedical Engineering Graduate Group (BMEGG) offers programs of study and research leading to two Master of Science degrees, Plan 1 (Thesis) and Plan 2 (Exam). The MS Plan 1 typically takes two years to complete, while the MS Plan 2 can be completed in 1 year. <span>Each student, together with an advisor, defines a specific course of study suited to individual goals. The</span> programs of study prepare students for professional work in the effective integration of engineering with medical and biological sciences. Additional information is available at <a href="https://bmegg.ucdavis.edu/">Biomedical Engineering Graduate Group</a>.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p class="diffchanged">The BMEGG curriculum requires strong competence in mathematics, engineering, and biology for successful completion of study. Prior course work in these areas is emphasized in the evaluation of applications, though some undergraduate training can be acquired after admission to the BMEGG. <span class="diffadded" title="Added content">For additional information, see <a href="https://bmegg.ucdavis.edu/academic-preparation">Academic Preparation</a>.</span></p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p class="diffadded"><span class="diffadded" title="Added content">Current degree requirements and program contacts are maintained at <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gbim">Biomedical Engineering</a>.</span></p>
<h3>Courses</h3>
<p class="diffadded"><span class="diffadded" title="Added content">See <a href="/courses-subject-code/bim/">Biomedical Engineering (BIM)</a>. Elective coursework will be selected with a Graduate Advisor to define a specific course of study suited to individual goals.</span></p>
<h3>Research Focus Areas</h3>
<p>Research strengths lie in the areas of: biomaterials &amp; devices; biomechanics &amp; mechanobiology; biomedical imaging &amp; biophotonics; computational &amp; synthetic biology; engineering education; molecular, cellular &amp; tissue engineering; and neuroengineering &amp; bioelectricity.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>Join us in a rich spectrum of advanced research at the molecular, cellular, tissue, systems, and organism levels, as well as in clinical practice. Gain advanced knowledge of the modeling of biological systems and the design of devices and procedures useful for human and veterinary medicine. Graduate with the skills necessary for professional research and teaching in the integration of engineering with biological and medical sciences. </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

