<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Business Analytics, Master of Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p>H. Rao Unnava, Ph.D., Dean<br/>
Carrie Beam, Ph.D., Academic Executive Director</p>
<h2>School Office</h2>
<p>Gallagher Hall; 530-752-7658; <a href="https://gsm.ucdavis.edu/master-science-business-analytics-msba">Master of Science in Business Analytics</a>; <a href="https://gsm.ucdavis.edu/faculty-and-research/faculty-directory?glossary_filter=All&amp;search=" target="_blank">Faculty</a></p>
<h2>Program of Study</h2>
<p>The Graduate School of Management Master of Science in Business Analytics program allows you to build competencies in analytics, data, business and practice and prepares you to be an innovative leader in this data-driven era. Advance your career by acquiring expertise in one of the most coveted skill sets in today’s, modern business environment—business analytics.</p>
<h3>Core Competencies</h3>
<p><em>Business</em>—<span>Build your business skills for achieving organizational impact through leadership, strategic thinking, communication and project management. </span></p>
<p><em>Data</em>—<span>Build your data skills as you learn core methods for acquiring, storing, handling and representing data.</span></p>
<p><em>Analytics</em>—Analytics is the discovery, interpretation and communication of meaningful patterns of data. Build your skills in core statistical and computational techniques such as data modeling, databases, regression, data mining, machine learning<strong>,</strong> operations research and artificial intelligence (AI) methods.</p>
<p><em>Practice</em>—<span>Our program gives you hands-on experience working with and implementing analytic projects in a business environment. Under the direction of program faculty and in small student teams, you will learn analytics by navigating the complete project lifecycle on business problems drawn from real industry data.</span></p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/smbx">Business Analytics</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Business Analytics Program integrates STEM perspective into business education and analysis, and prepares students to thrive as an innovative leader in the digital economy. The yearlong project course gives graduate students the opportunity to solve complex business problems starting with an analytical framework, collecting and analyzing data, extracting insights, and presenting recommendations for action to the client company. </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

