<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Chemical Engineering, Doctor of Philosophy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Program in the Department of Chemical Engineering</h2>
<p>The Department of Chemical Engineering is home to a top-ranked graduate program in Chemical Engineering. We offer a unique environment for graduate studies- we are large enough to boast world-renowned faculty and state-of-the-art research facilities, yet small enough to give every graduate student personal attention. </p>
<p>The Chemical Engineering Graduate Program provides students with a strong grounding in the fundamentals and explores critical applications in a wide range of process systems.</p>
<h2>The Doctoral Degree in Chemical Engineering</h2>
<p>The doctoral (Ph.D.) degree prepares students to solve complex, long-term research problems. You can expect to graduate in four to five years and to work on a large research project, culminating in a dissertation. The majority of our doctoral graduates end up in industry careers, usually in research and product development positions. Others go on to careers in academia, either as a postdoctoral researcher or an assistant professor. Major research areas include Energy, Environment, Synthetic Biology, and Biotechnology. </p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gech">Chemical Engineering</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://che.engineering.ucdavis.edu/graduate" target="_blank">Chemical Engineering Graduate Program</a>; 530-752-7952</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>UC Davis students gain advanced knowledge of chemical engineering theory and its relationship to related engineering processes. Thanks to our individualized mentoring and research opportunities, our graduate students are well-prepared for careers in either academia or industry. </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

