<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Chemical Engineering, Master of Engineering</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Program in the Department of Chemical Engineering</h2>
<p>The Department of Chemical Engineering is home to a top-ranked graduate program in Chemical Engineering. We offer a unique environment for graduate studies- we are large enough to boast world-renowned faculty and state-of-the-art-research facilities, yet small enough to give every graduate student personal attention. </p>
<p>The Chemical Engineering Graduate Program provides students with a strong grounding in the fundamentals and explores critical applications in a wide range of process systems.</p>
<h2>The Master of Engineering in Chemical Engineering</h2>
<p>Our Master of Engineering in Chemical Engineering program is full-time, 9-12 months long and the ideal opportunity for students who are interested in a career in the process engineering field and increased earning potential.</p>
<p>The M.Eng. program features project-based learning, hands-on engineering design experiences and a strong emphasis on professional skills, including problem-solving, critical thinking, and collaboration. M.Eng. students can tailor their degree experience with flexible electives, a capstone project, and internship opportunities. </p>
<h3><strong style="font-size:1.7425rem; font-style:normal; font-weight:800">Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</strong></h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gech">Chemical Engineering</a>.</p>
<p class="diffadded"><span class="diffadded" title="Added content"><a href="https://che.engineering.ucdavis.edu/graduate" target="_blank">Chemical Engineering Graduate Program</a>; 530-752-7952</span></p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>UC Davis students gain advanced knowledge of chemical engineering theory and its relationship to related engineering processes. Thanks to our individualized mentoring and research opportunities, our graduate students are well-prepared for careers in either academia or industry. </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

