<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Civil &amp; Environmental Engineering, Doctor of Philosophy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Doctor of Philosophy</h2>
<p>Biotechnology Designated Ph.D. emphasis also available.</p>
<p><a href="https://cee.engineering.ucdavis.edu/graduate" target="_blank">Civil &amp; Environmental Engineering</a></p>
<p>The Department of Civil &amp; Environmental Engineering integrates research, education and professional service in areas related to civil infrastructure and the environment. Graduate students benefit from close working relationships with professors who are the leading international experts in their field. With over forty faculty members and research expenditures exceeding $20M, graduate students are supported in their study and research by robust funding, and they have access to state-of-the-art research facilities within the program and in interdisciplinary CEE faculty-led centers across campus. Our graduates go on to serve the profession and academia by advancing the leading edge of fundamental knowledge, as well as engineering practice.</p>
<p>Generous financial support is available in the form of research assistantships, teaching assistantships, fellowships and financial aid. Nearly all Ph.D. students are fully supported through one or more of these paths, or through external fellowships.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gece">Civil &amp; Environmental Engineering</a>.</p>
<h2>Research Area Highlights</h2>
<ul>
	<li>Alternative fuel transportation infrastructure</li>
	<li>Earthquake engineering</li>
	<li>Environmental engineering</li>
	<li>Environmental planning and management</li>
	<li>Geotechnical engineering</li>
	<li>Hydraulics and fluid mechanics</li>
	<li>Hydrology</li>
	<li>Structural engineering</li>
	<li>Structural health monitoring</li>
	<li>Structural mechanics</li>
	<li>Systems planning and design</li>
	<li>Transportation engineering</li>
	<li>Transportation planning and design</li>
	<li>Water resources engineering</li>
</ul>
<h2>Research Facilities &amp; Partnerships</h2>
<ul>
	<li>Air Quality Research Center</li>
	<li>Center for Bio-mediated &amp; Bio-inspired Geotechnics</li>
	<li>Center for Geotechnical Modeling</li>
	<li>Center for Watershed Sciences</li>
	<li>Center for Water-Energy Efficiency</li>
	<li>Institute of Transportation Studies</li>
	<li>J. Amorocho Hydraulics Laboratory (JAHL)</li>
	<li>John Muir Institute of the Environment</li>
	<li>Pavement Research Center &amp; Advanced Transportation Infrastructure Research Center</li>
	<li>Tahoe Environmental Research Center</li>
	<li>Western Cooling Efficiency Center</li>
</ul>
<p>Complete Information is on our website.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>Students gain advanced knowledge of designing, building, operating and maintaining the physical infrastructure and protecting the natural environment that together support human society in an economically and environmentally sustainable manner. The program will develop the skills necessary for professional research and teaching in engineering and environmental planning management.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

