<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Community Development, Master of Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p>Brittany Chambers Butcher, Ph.D., Chairperson of the Group</p>
<h2>Group Office</h2>
<p>129 Hunt Hall; 530-752-4119; <a href="https://communitydevelopment.ucdavis.edu/contact-us-0">Graduate Program Coordinator</a>; <a href="http://communitydevelopment.ucdavis.edu" target="_blank">Community Development Graduate Group</a>; <a href="http://communitydevelopment.ucdavis.edu/people/faculty.php">Faculty</a></p>
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Community Development Graduate Group (CDGG) offers an inter-disciplinary program of study that leads to the M.S. degree. The program emphasizes interdisciplinary, collaborative, and project-based learning, as well as community-engaged scholarship. The CDGG challenges students to integrate theory and practice, to develop constructive solutions to contemporary problems, and to lead in building a healthy, sustainable, and equitable society. Graduate study in the CDGG prepares individuals to work within government, for-profit and non-profit community development organizations in the realm of social and economic change, or to prepare them for further doctoral studies in related programs. Particular strengths of the program include: community economic development; community organizing and organizations in under-served communities; environmental justice and planning; education; ethnic studies; local impacts of globalization and trans-nationalism; rural and urban political development and change; sustainable agriculture and food systems; and women and gender studies.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>Applicants to this program can prepare themselves by enrolling for upper division courses in the social or behavioral sciences, e.g., anthropology, economics, sociology, psychology, geography, urban studies or political science, and courses in community studies.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gcmd">Community Development</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>This program prepares students for careers in nonprofit and governmental organizations as organizers, administrators, planners, researchers, advocates, and policymakers.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

