<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Computer Science, Doctor of Philosophy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Graduate Group in Computer Science offers programs of study leading to M.S. and Ph.D. degrees in Computer Science. The diverse expertise of the faculty brings a wide variety of research interests to the program. Research strengths lie in algorithms, artificial intelligence, computational biology, computer architecture, computer graphics and visualization, computer vision, computer science education, computer security and cryptography, computer networks, data science, database systems, machine learning, molecular computing, nanotechnology, natural language processing, network science, parallel and distributed systems, program specifications and verification, programming languages and compilers, quantum computing, scientific computation, social and ethical issues of computing, and software engineering. Interdisciplinary research in computer science is encouraged.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>Normal preparation for the program is a bachelor's degree in either computer science or in a closely related field (such as electrical engineering or mathematics, with substantial course work in computer science). Applications are also considered from students with outstanding records in other disciplines. Ph.D. students must pass a qualifying oral examination and complete a dissertation demonstrating original research in an area approved by the Graduate Group.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gcsi">Computer Science</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>If you are interested in computer science research opportunities, UC Davis has the program for you.  Students who study with our Graduate Group in Computer Science are well prepared for careers in academia or industry.  </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

