<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Comparative Literature, Master of Arts</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p><span style="color:rgb(0, 0, 0)">The Comparative Literature thesis-based M.A. program prepares students for doctoral research or professional employment. Our graduate students are supported by a large group of core and affiliated faculty in Comparative Literature. Our faculty hold cross-appointments with the departments of East Asian Languages &amp; Cultures, English, French &amp; Italian, German &amp; Russian, Middle East/South Asian Languages, and Religious Studies. We welcome applications from students with a strong humanities background who wish to strengthen their expertise in comparative literature and criticism.</span></p>
<p>The program combines core courses on the theory and practice of comparison with broad opportunities for work in specific languages and literatures. Students will write a Masters thesis with the support of a thesis committee and a collaborative thesis-writing group.</p>
<h2>Preparation</h2>
<p>Consideration for program admission requires evidence of the following:</p>
<ul>
	<li>A strong undergraduate record in any humanities major.</li>
	<li>Fluent reading, writing, and speaking knowledge in one language that is not the student’s native language.</li>
	<li>A clear commitment to the study of a second language that is not the student’s native language.</li>
</ul>
<p>For deadlines and application requirements, see <a href="https://complit.ucdavis.edu/graduate-admissions">Comparative Literature Graduate Admissions</a>.</p>
<h2>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h2>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gcom">Comparative Literature</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Comparative Literature Graduate Program enables students to gain an advanced knowledge of several literatures in their original languages in a theoretically and historically informed context. Students graduate with the skills necessary for professional research and teaching in comparative literature, and related disciplines world literature, critical theory and the humanities.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

