<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Cultural Studies, Doctor of Philosophy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Graduate Group in Cultural Studies at UC Davis offers an interdisciplinary approach to the study of culture and society that highlights how sexuality, race, ability, citizenship, gender, nationality, class and language organize embodied identities, social relations and cultural objects. With the close guidance and supervision of a faculty committee, students in the program pursue interdisciplinary research in areas including studies of comparative and critical race, ecocriticism, fashion, queer theory, media and popular cultural representation, science and technology, travel and tourism, food, physical and cognitive abilities, cultural geography,  transnational culture and politics, globalization, religion, rhetoric, performance, and critical theory. Although both the Ph.D. and M.A. are offered, applications are only accepted for the Ph.D. program, and the M.A. is available as a terminal degree in route to the Ph.D.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>Normal preparation for the program is a bachelor's degree in a related field. Terminal M.A. students must pass an examination. Ph.D. students must pass a qualifying examination, a comprehensive examination, and complete a dissertation demonstrating original research in an area approved by the Graduate Group. In addition to the standard UC Davis graduate application (which requires a statement of purpose), we also require three letters of recommendation, transcripts, writing sample (ten-page minimum, not exceeding twenty pages), and a fellowship application.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gclt">Cultural Studies</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>Cultural Studies at UC Davis offers an interdisciplinary approach to the study of culture and society that highlights how sexuality, race, ability, citizenship, gender, nationality, class and language organize embodied identities, social relations and cultural objects. Our program, one of the few advanced degrees in Cultural Studies in the United States, emphasizes the linked analyses of these factors in relation to local community formations, transnationalism, (post)(neo)colonialism, and globalization.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

