<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Design, Master of Fine Arts</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Master of Fine Arts</h2>
<p>The M.F.A. in Design at UC Davis is a two-year program that encourages interdisciplinary approaches through research and practice aligning with social and environmental responsibility. We offer graduate students a unique opportunity to work with faculty in the Department of Design and across departments in one of the nation’s top public research universities. Design faculty expertise includes design theory, exhibition, fashion, history, information, interactivity, interior architecture, immersion, lighting, product, textiles, time-based, visual communication, wearables, and more. Students are encouraged to build connections across campus to expand perspectives and deepen understandings. Students’ progress through core courses alongside their cohort members while advancing their individual research. Core courses are augmented by graduate-level independent and group studies and upper-division undergraduate level electives. The M.F.A. program culminates in a written- and project-based thesis publicized in a major graduate exhibition. The program is committed to equity, diversity, inclusion and public engagement.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="http://arts.ucdavis.edu/design-graduate-program" target="_blank">M.F.A. Program in Design</a>.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gdes">Design</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Master Fine Arts degree in Design is a program that encourages interdisciplinary approaches through research and practice aligning with social and environmental responsibility.  Come work with Design faculty who are experts in areas such as;  design theory, exhibition, lighting, textiles, visual communication, wearables, and more. The program is committed to equity, diversity, inclusion and public engagement.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

