<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Nursing Science &amp; Health-Care Leadership, Doctor of Nursing Practice—Family Nurse Practitioner</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<p>Charleen Singh, Ph.D., M.B.A., M.S.N./E.D., F.N.P.-B.C., C.W.O.C.N., C.N.E., W.O.C.N.F., R.N., Director for the Doctor of Nursing Practice — Family Nurse Practitioner Degree Program</p>
<h2>Nursing Science &amp; Health-Care Leadership, Doctor of Nursing Practice—Family Nurse Practitioner</h2>
<p>The Nursing Science &amp; Health-Care Leadership, Doctor of Nursing Practice—Family Nurse Practitioner at UC Davis is a post-baccalaureate program that prepares new family nurse practitioners. The DNP-FNP program is a three-year hybrid program that combines distanced-based education with four on-campus immersions. Students learn to engage in patient- and family-centered, evidence-based primary care. Through reflective practice and interprofessional collaboration, alumni are advanced practice providers who lead bold system change and promote health care innovation by informing and advancing health policy and health equity locally, nationally and globally.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gndp">Doctor of Nursing Practice - Family Nurse Practitioner</a>.</p>
<h3>Faculty</h3>
<p>The UC Davis Nursing Science and Health-Care Leadership Graduate Group includes a wide cross-section of academic disciplines with faculty from the Betty Irene Moore School of Nursing as well as UC Davis Health and other UC Davis schools, colleges, and departments. Within the graduate group faculty are experts in nursing, medicine, health informatics, nutrition, pharmacy, biostatistics, public health and various clinical specialties.</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Doctor of Nursing Practice — Family Nurse Practitioner Program  prepares advanced practice providers to engage in patient- and family-centered, evidence-based primary care. Through reflective practice and interprofessional collaboration, you are prepared to be leaders who effect bold system change and promote health care innovation by informing and advancing health policy and health equity locally, nationally and globally. </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

