<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Ecology, Master of Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p>Robert Hijmans, Ph.D., Chairperson of the Group</p>
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Graduate Group in Ecology offers M.S. and Ph.D. degrees. Ecology is a science that integrates numerous fields of study to attain deep understanding of natural and societal influences on the distribution, abundances,  behaviors, traits, and ecosystem functions of organisms. In order to accommodate varied student interests, the Group has developed several 'areas of emphasis' with specialized programs of study: agricultural ecology, conservation ecology, ecological genomics and genetics, ecosystems and landscape ecology, ecotoxicology and  physiological ecology, environmental policy and human ecology, integrative ecology, marine ecology, and restoration ecology. For further details, contact the Group office.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>Appropriate preparation is undergraduate work in any of the biological, social or behavioral, and physical sciences, mathematics or engineering. Applicants will normally be expected to have completed the following courses during the undergraduate years or shortly after matriculating: one course each in introductory biology, general chemistry, physics, calculus, statistics, and an upper division introduction to ecology course.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gecl">Ecology</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>Our Ecology graduate programs offer students a combination of both basic and applied ecology. Students gain advanced knowledge in one of the following areas:  agricultural ecology, conservation ecology, ecological genomics and genetics, ecosystems and landscape ecology, ecotoxicology, environmental policy &amp; human ecology, integrative ecology, marine ecology, physiological ecology, or restoration ecology.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

