<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Education, Doctor of Philosophy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p>Francisco (Paco) Martorell, Ph.D., GGE Chair; term ends June 30, 2026</p>
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Graduate Group in Education offers programs of study and research leading to the Ph.D. degree. Students may concentrate in; language, literacy and culture; learning and mind sciences; mathematics education; school organization and educational policy; or science and agriculture education. Students may also combine these fields of study with designated emphasis areas such as Critical Theory; Second Language Acquisition, Women's Studies, and Writing, Rhetoric, and Composition Studies. Detailed information regarding graduate study may be obtained by writing the Graduate Coordinator or see <a href="https://education.ucdavis.edu/phd-education">Education Ph.D. Program</a>.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>Students should have earned a Bachelor's or M.A. degree or the equivalent in a discipline relevant to their proposed emphasis program. For example, students applying for the mathematics education emphasis should have earned the B.A. or M.A. or M.A.T. degree in mathematics or mathematics education. The M.A. is available en route to the Ph.D.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gedp">Education (Ph.D.)</a>.</p>
<h3>Courses</h3>
<p>See <a href="/courses-subject-code/edu/">Education (EDU)</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>UC Davis is located close to California’s state capital of Sacramento, providing students a rich set of opportunities and networks for influencing education policy.  Graduates of our program gain deep knowledge of educational theory and practice related to strengthening schools and other educational settings.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

