<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>English, Minor</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>The Minor Program</h2>
<p>Pursuing a minor in English allows students to develop their abilities to read critically and to write clearly while enjoying the pleasures that great literature has to offer. To complete the minor, students take five upper division courses, at least four of which focus on literature, film, or other media. Choices within the curriculum are unlimited by historical period, and can include a course in creative writing. All minors have the opportunity to work with distinguished writers, critics, scholars, and teachers.</p>
<h3>Career Alternatives</h3>
<p>Graduates have found the minor to be an excellent complement to their training in other fields, helping to demonstrate their writing and critical thinking skills to employers and graduate schools.</p>



]]>
</informationtext>
<requirementstext name="Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<table class="sc_courselist">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup>
<col class="codecol"/>
<col class="titlecol"/>
<col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/>
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr class="hidden noscript">
<th scope="col">Code</th>
<th scope="col">Title</th>
<th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="even firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Five upper division (100 level) English (ENL) courses; at least four of these must be literature courses (numbered 107-186).</span></td><td class="hourscol">20</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent"><a href="/courses-subject-code/enl/">English (ENL)</a></span></div></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="listsum"><td colspan="2">Total Units</td><td class="hourscol">20</td></tr></tbody>
</table>

]]>
</requirementstext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The English minor joined with any major on campus gives students useful preparation for positions requiring orderly and clear thinking and expression. Students find that pursuing a minor in English allows them to develop the ability to read and write critically while enjoying all the pleasures that great literature has to offer.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

