<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Environmental Policy &amp; Management, Master of Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Master of Science in Environmental Policy &amp; Management (EPM) program provides advanced training in applying environmental science to real-world environmental policy and management issues. The EPM program sets itself apart by targeting students with interdisciplinary backgrounds who seek applied professional careers in environmental policy and management. The focus is on building quantitative skills for practice-oriented careers in environmental policy and management for more information, see <a href="http://epm.ucdavis.edu/" target="_blank">Environmental Policy &amp; Management</a>.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>Before enrolling, a student should have completed a program of study equivalent to a B.A. or B.S. in a Science, Technology, Engineering &amp; Math (STEM) field. Students without a prior degree in a STEM field are required to complete preparatory courses, or their equivalents to demonstrate a fundamental scientific background appropriate for environmental policy. Applicants are expected to have passed the equivalent of the following courses: one upper-division course in environmental science or ecology; one upper-division course in microeconomics or policy analysis; and one upper-division course in statistics or mathematical modeling. Prior coursework in economics (intermediate microeconomics) is recommended, but not required. </p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gepm">Environmental Policy &amp; Management</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Environmental Policy and Management Program focus is interdisciplinary training on the roles of science that is directly relevant to real-world environmental policy and management issues. Students will develop problem-solving skills involving analysis, communication, and negotiation that are needed in policy-making and management positions.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

