<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Horticulture &amp; Agronomy, Master of Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Graduate Group in Horticulture &amp; Agronomy offers programs of study leading to M.S. and Ph.D. degrees for students interested in the science and management of agricultural crops, including their ecology, physiology, genetics, and post-harvest management, as well as the interaction of agricultural crops with the environment. The M.S. program is designed to focus on a cropping system, such as agronomy, environmental horticulture, pomology, vegetable crops, viticulture and weed science. Within that cropping system, the student can specialize in one of a number of areas, including agroecology, biotechnology, breeding and crop improvement, crop physiology, crop production, floriculture, landscape horticulture, mineral nutrition, modeling, nursery production, pest management, plant growth and development, postharvest physiology, revegetation/restoration, and water relations. Research may be conducted within these areas with an applied or basic focus, but in association with a cropping system.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>For both M.S. and Ph.D. programs, a level of competence equivalent to that of a sound undergraduate program in Plant Science is required. This includes coursework in general biology, chemistry, organic chemistry, physics, statistics, genetics, plant physiology, and soil science. A few limited deficiencies in any of these areas can be made up after admission to the graduate program. Specific requirements are outlined in detail on the group's website. The graduate advisor, the major professor, and the student will design a program of advanced courses to meet individual academic needs within one of the specializations.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/ghag">Horticulture &amp; Agronomy</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>Horticulture and Agronomy has an applied or basic plant research research focus but always in association with an agricultural system. Examples of such systems include vegetable crops, field crops (grains), ornamentals, orchard systems, viticulture, etc. Research within these systems ranges from cell biology processes to landscape scale patterns, i.e., detailed plant physiology to global modelling.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

