<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Immunology, Doctor of Philosophy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Graduate Group in Immunology offers an interdisciplinary program of study in an exciting field of biology and medicine leading to M.S. and Ph.D. degrees. Participating faculty from various UC Davis Schools and Departments provide research opportunities in diverse areas of applied immunology. Areas of focus include infection and immunity (including host response regulation to parasites, viruses and bacteria), nutrition and immunity, autoimmunity, immune regulation, neuroimmunology, cancer therapy and immune mediators and their uses for diagnosis and treatment.</p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>Applicants for candidacy to these programs should have completed undergraduate preparation in mathematics, physics, chemistry, biochemistry, molecular and cellular biology or related biological and medical sciences.</p>
<p>For work leading to the Ph.D. degree, the requirements include cell biology, chemical immunology, cellular immunology, immunohematology, and advanced immunology. In addition to these general requirements, more specialized preparation in at least one of the following is required: (a) microbiological specialties (bacteriology, virology, parasitology, medical microbiology); (b) zoological specialties (cell biology, endocrinology, embryology, proto-zoology, histology, cytology, physiology); (c) medical specialties (pathology, anatomy, pharmacology, clinical pathology, reproduction, hematology, epidemiology); (d) biochemistry/biophysics specialties (biologically active molecules, control mechanisms); (e) genetic specialties (developmental genetics, population genetics, cytogenetics, molecular genetics).</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gimm">Immunology</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>If you are looking for opportunities to advance your knowledge of immunology in disease pathogenesis and therapy, the Immunology Graduate Group offers an interdisciplinary, flexible program.  Diverse research and strong integrated curriculum us available un many areas of immunology such as infection immunity, vaccine development, allergy, autoimmunity, and use of immune mediators  for diagnosis and treatment. </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

