<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>International Agricultural Development, Master of Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The International Agricultural Development M.S. degree program prepares students for careers in global agricultural and rural development. This is an interdisciplinary program designed to provide students with knowledge and skills that will enable them to implement, facilitate, and manage programs that enhance agricultural development, resource management, and rural life. Coursework and research is especially, but not exclusively, focused on issues facing developing countries and less-industrialized regions. </p>
<p>Students are prepared to realize biological and technological improvement in agricultural and natural systems to facilitate social innovation. Training in International Agricultural Development includes both breadth and depth components. Breadth components, required of all M.S. students, aim to establish an understanding of the issues in international development as they relate to agriculture and the environment. These include the history and philosophy of development, leadership and management techniques, fundamentals of farming systems, and agricultural economics.</p>
<p>Through coursework and an independent research or capstone project, students acquire depth in their own area of specialization within the agricultural and social sciences. The areas are flexible and could include agricultural and resource economics, agricultural engineering, agronomy, animal science, anthropology, aquaculture, avian science, community development, ecology, economics, entomology, environmental design, environmental toxicology, food science, gender, geography, horticulture, nutrition, plant pathology, plant biology, plant protection and pest management, political science, preventive veterinary medicine, range science, sociology, soil science, sustainable agriculture, vegetable crops, viticulture, and water science.</p>
<p>Practical and on-site experience with development issues is encouraged through an independent research or capstone project. Students obtain guidance from partner organizations and the group's faculty members, who possess a wide range of academic experience in international development.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/giad">International Agricultural Development</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>This program provides students with knowledge and skills to implement, facilitate, and manage programs that enhance agricultural development, resource management, and rural life, particularly in developing and less-industrialized regions of the world. The required breadth components provide students with an understanding of international development issues related to agriculture and the environment. These include the history and philosophy of development, leadership and management techniques, fundamentals of crop and livestock farming systems, and agricultural economics. The depth component is acquired through a student’s area of specialization (pest management, soil science, viticulture, etc.)</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

