<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Doctor of Jurisprudence</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p>The University of California Davis School of Law offers a three-year professional curriculum leading to the degree of Juris Doctor. Within a uniquely supportive atmosphere, law students have access to a comprehensive modern law school curriculum taught by a nationally and internationally distinguished faculty. The School offers a full range of traditional law courses, opportunities for practical experience through clinical programs, and in-depth study of an area of law in an individualized program of classroom work, research, writing, or experience in the community. It further provides professional skills training in interviewing and counseling, negotiation and dispute resolution  and trial practice. The School of Law seeks to promote critical evaluation of law and legal institutions in a broad perspective, integrating non-legal disciplines with professional legal education.</p>
<p>UC Davis Law School is fully accredited by the American Bar Association, is a member of the Association of American Law Schools, and has a chapter of the Order of the Coif.</p>
<h2>Program of Study</h2>
<p>The professional curriculum requires six semesters for completion and extends over a period of three years. It is for full-time students only; no part-time or evening program is offered. New students are admitted only at the beginning of the fall semester.</p>
<p>After satisfactorily completing the professional curriculum of 88 semester units and the required period of resident study, you will receive the degree of Juris Doctor (J.D.). Students who fail to attain satisfactory grades may be required to withdraw from the School at the end of any academic year.</p>
<p>The first year’s work is prescribed and provides the essential foundation for subsequent legal study. Satisfactory completion of the first-year courses is, in all cases, prerequisite to second- and third-year courses.</p>
<h2>J.D. Degree Requirements</h2>
<p>To graduate, students must meet these law degree qualification requirements:</p>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Pass all required courses. </strong>The first year required courses include Law 200 Introduction to Law, Law 203 Civil Procedure, Law 205 Constitutional Law I, Law 202 Contracts, Law 206 Criminal Law, Law 207 Legal Research &amp; Writing I, Law 208 Legal Research &amp; Writing II, Law 200S Lawyering Process, Law 201 Property, and Law 204 Torts.  </li>
	<li><strong>Earn 88 semester units. </strong>This must be completed in no more than six semesters unless a student is approved for an extended program by the Senior Assistant Dean for Student Affairs. </li>
	<li><strong>Earn at least 68 classroom-based law units. </strong>Courses that do not count towards the 68 classroom-based law units include independent study units (Law 419, 419A, 499, or 499A), co-curricular units (law review, law journals, and competitions), externship placement units (may not exceed 14 units), and non-law units taken in other UC Davis departments. If a student graduates with exactly 88 units, they may have a maximum of 20 non-classroom-based units.</li>
	<li><strong>Complete six semesters in residence. </strong>&quot;In residence&quot; means that the student has earned at least 10 units during that semester. A &quot;semester-away&quot; through an approved exchange program or an approved semester-long visit at another ABA accredited law school, count as a semester in residence. (Students may not take more than 17 units per semester). </li>
	<li><strong>Complete Law 258 Professional Responsibility or 258A Legal Ethics and Organizational Practice. </strong></li>
	<li><strong>Satisfy the skills requirement of regulation <a href="https://law.ucdavis.edu/students/registrar/regulations#1.4">1.4B</a>. </strong>In either the second or third year, students must take one or more course(s), totaling at least six credits, designated as satisfying instruction in professional skills.</li>
	<li><strong>Satisfy the <a href="https://law.ucdavis.edu/sites/g/files/dgvnsk10866/files/inline-files/Writing-Requirement-Certificate%281%29.pdf">writing requirement</a> of regulation <a href="https://law.ucdavis.edu/students/registrar/regulations#1.4">1.4C</a>. </strong>In either the second or third year, students must write an individually authored work of rigorous intellectual effort of at least 20 typewritten, double spaced pages, excluding footnotes. At least one draft of the paper is required to be exchanged between student and professor and feedback should be incorporated before the final submission of the paper. Each semester, a number of courses are offered which can satisfy the writing requirement. This is generally noted in the <a href="https://law.ucdavis.edu/students/registrar/course-descriptions">course's description</a>. </li>
	<li><strong>Have a cumulative grade point average of at least 2.3 at the end of the final semester. </strong></li>
	<li><strong>Adhere to the 14-credit limit on externships. </strong>Of the semester credits required for graduation, a total of not more than 14 total units may be earned in <a href="https://law.ucdavis.edu/externships/index.html">externship placement units</a>. </li>
	<li><strong>Satisfy the Bias, Antiracism and Cultural Competency requirement.</strong> (Beginning with the Class of 2026). Students must successfully complete one course designated by the law school as meeting the standards of significant instruction in Bias, Antiracism and Cross-cultural competencies. The list of qualifying courses is <a href="https://law.ucdavis.edu/students/registrar/course-descriptions">here</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Please note that a student may not use the same course to satisfy more than one of the following academic requirements: </strong>1) Advanced Writing, 2) Bias, Antiracism, and Cultural-Competency, and 3) Professional Skills. For example, a course that is used to satisfy the writing requirement cannot also be used to satisfy the professional skills requirement.</li>
</ul>
<p>The full Law School Regulations are at <a href="https://law.ucdavis.edu/students/registrar/regulations">Regulations</a>.</p>
<h2>Concurrent Degree Programs</h2>
<p>Individual students may find a concurrent degree involving law and another discipline such as economics, business, sociology, or science advantageous. To support this kind of study, the School, in conjunction with other schools and university departments, has established Concurrent Degree Programs. Under these programs, a student may work toward a J.D. degree and a master’s degree in another discipline at the same time. Students working toward a combined degree are required to spend their first year at the law school.</p>
<p>Normally, a Combined Degree Program will take at least four years. You will usually be able to earn between 6 to 10 semester-hours of law school credit for work in the related discipline and may be able to complete the combined degrees in less time than it would take to earn the two degrees separately. The first year of the Concurrent Degree Program must be taken entirely in the School of Law. During the remaining years, course work may be divided between the law school and the related discipline. You must satisfy the admission requirements for both programs and file applications with both units.</p>
<p>Students have pursued degree programs in combination with UC Davis departments for the M.A. degree in economics, philosophy, computer science, and sociology, and with the School of Management for the M.B.A. degree. The law school will attempt to work out an additional program if you are interested in other disciplines. You may enroll in the Concurrent Degree Program any time before the beginning of your third year in law school. If you are interested in pursuing a Concurrent Degree Program, and have made a separate application to another school or department, you should notify the School of Law if that application is accepted.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>At UC Davis School of Law, your academic and professional success is of utmost importance to the faculty, staff, and administration. Classes are small, professors are world-class legal scholars and teachers, and the staff and administration are accessible, caring, and friendly. In addition, the Academic Success Program provides resources to assist with all aspects of the study of law.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

