<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Letters &amp; Science, Bachelor of Arts, Individual</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p><span style="color:rgb(0, 0, 0)">1207 Social Sciences &amp; Humanities Building (Undergraduate Education &amp; Advising office); </span><a href="https://lettersandscience.ucdavis.edu/advising" target="_blank">Advising</a></p>
<h2>The Major Program</h2>
<p>The Individual Major, an integrated program composed of courses from two or more disciplines, is designed by the student and is subject to approval by the faculty advisor and appropriate college committees. This major enables a student to pursue a specific interest that cannot be accommodated within the framework of an existing major. It must clearly and specifically meet the student’s educational goals as well as meet university and college academic standards.</p>
<h3>Student Proposal</h3>
<p><strong>Prior to submission of proposal, student must meet the following criteria: minimum overall GPA or 3.0 as well as a minimum GPA of 3.0 in all preparatory courses for the selected major.</strong> A student who wishes to propose an individual major must submit the proposal to the Faculty Committee on Individual Majors in the College of Letters &amp; Science prior to reaching 120 units. The proposal must be submitted by the end of the fourth week of the quarter. This proposal will consist of (1) an essay, identifying the specific educational and professional objectives, including an indication of why the objectives cannot be met within existing majors, (2) a list of courses planned to complete the major, and (3) faculty advisor recommendations. The proposal will be reviewed and a decision provided the quarter of submittal. It is important that you carefully review the information in the <a href="https://lettersandscience.ucdavis.edu/sites/g/files/dgvnsk10716/files/files/page/individual-major-handbook_0.pdf">Individual Major Handbook</a>.</p>
<h3>Honors Program</h3>
<p>By the fourth week of the last quarter of the junior year, students potentially eligible for high or highest honors at graduation (see <a href="https://lettersandscience.ucdavis.edu/deans-honors-list-and-graduation-honors" target="_blank">Dean's Honors List &amp; Graduation with Honors</a>), may petition the Individual Majors Committee for tentative acceptance into an honors program.</p>
<p>Final admission will depend upon the Committee's approval of a senior thesis prospectus that has been agreed upon by the student and faculty advisor. The prospectus must be presented to the Committee by the end of the fourth full week of instruction of the first quarter of the senior year. Graduation with high or highest honors will be conditional upon both the maintenance of the required grade point average and the satisfactory completion of the senior thesis project. Students who anticipate doing a senior honors thesis should allow up to 3 units of independent study in the program during each of two quarters in the senior year as course options.</p>
<h3>Major Advisor (Selected By Student)</h3>
<p><strong>Principal Advisor. </strong>A faculty member in a teaching department or program in the College of Letters &amp; Science in the major field of emphasis.<br/>
<strong>Secondary Advisor. </strong>A faculty member from a secondary area of interest.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<requirementstext name="Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<p>The major requirements below are in addition to meeting <a href="/undergraduate-education/university-degree-requirements/">University Degree Requirements</a> &amp; <a href="/undergraduate-education/college-degree-requirements/">College Degree Requirements</a>; unless otherwise noted. The minimum number of units required for the <span class="title-main">Letters &amp; Science Individual Bachelor of Arts </span>is 45.</p>
<table class="sc_courselist">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup>
<col class="codecol"/>
<col class="titlecol"/>
<col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/>
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr class="hidden noscript">
<th scope="col">Code</th>
<th scope="col">Title</th>
<th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Preparatory Subject Matter</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Lower division courses basic to the program or needed to satisfy prerequisites for upper division requirements.</span></td><td class="hourscol">0</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Preparatory Subject Matter Subtotal</span></td><td class="hourscol">0</td></tr>
<tr class="odd areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Depth Subject Matter</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Upper division units must include:</span></td><td class="hourscol">45-54</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">(a) Interrelated and complementary courses from two or more departments which provide a unified pattern and focus.</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">(b) At least 30 units from Letters &amp; Science teaching departments or programs.</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">(c) No more than 10 units in courses numbered 194H, 198 &amp; 199.</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">(d) For the A.B. degree, a maximum of 80 units toward the major.</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Depth Subject Matter Subtotal</span></td><td class="hourscol">45-54</td></tr>
<tr class="listsum"><td colspan="2">Total Units</td><td class="hourscol">45-54</td></tr></tbody>
</table>

]]>
</requirementstext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>Are you interested in the study of language structure? Linguists investigate how people obtain their knowledge about language, how this knowledge interacts with other cognitive processes, how it varies across speakers and geographic regions, and how to model this knowledge computationally.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

