<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Master of Management, Online Master of Management </title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p>H. Rao Unnava, Ph.D., Dean<br/>
Hemant Bhargava, Ph.D., Associate Dean<br/>
Joseph Chen, Ph.D., Program Chair</p>
<h2>School Office</h2>
<p>Gallagher Hall; 530-752-7658; <a href="https://gsm.ucdavis.edu/master-management">Master of Management</a>; <a href="https://gsm.ucdavis.edu/degrees/online-master-management">Online Master of Management</a>; <a href="https://gsm.ucdavis.edu/faculty-and-research">Faculty</a></p>
<h2>Master of Management</h2>
<p><span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff10" title="Added content">Master of Management program from the University</span> of <span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff11" title="Added content">California, Davis, is designed for recent undergraduates and early-career professionals.</span> <span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff31" title="Added content">In nine months, you can graduate with fundamental leadership skills, a custom-tailored career roadmap and access to corporate connections across Northern California and beyond.</span></p>
<h2><span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff14" title="Added content">Online Master of Management </span></h2>
<p><span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff15" title="Added content">The Online Master of Management from</span> the <span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff16" title="Added content">University of California, Davis, is the first of its kind at a University of California management school.</span> <span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff33" title="Added content">It offers early career professionals, recent undergraduates and career changers with a pathway to leadership roles in business. Students gain the knowledge, skills and network you need to jumpstart your business career in only 15 months.</span></p>
<h3><span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff34" title="Added content">Academics &amp; Curriculum</span></h3>
<p><span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff35" title="Added content">Modeled after UC Davis’ highly regarded MBA program, the Master of Management curriculum equips you with a strong foundation in the functional areas of business, such as accounting, economics, finance, marketing and strategy. </span></p>
<h3><span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff19" title="Added content">Powerful Connections</span></h3>
<p><span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff20" title="Added content">Through a collaborative learning environment,</span> you <span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff21" title="Added content">will build strong connections</span> with <span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff22" title="Added content">globally ranked professors</span> and <span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff23" title="Added content">motivated students who will know you by name and work with you to meet your educational and professional goals.</span></p>
<ul>
	<li><span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff38" title="Added content">Guidance from research faculty and instructors who are diverse thought leaders.</span></li>
	<li><span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff40" title="Added content">A focus on innovation, hands-on experience and trailblazing research.</span></li>
	<li><span class="diffadded" id="htmldiff42" title="Added content">In the final quarter of the program, you will need to pass a comprehensive examination that tests your mastery of the course material as well as your ability to synthesize learning across key subject areas.</span></li>
</ul>
]]>
</informationtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

