<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Public Health Sciences, Master of Public Health</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://health.ucdavis.edu/phs/education/mph/">Master of Public Health</a>; <a href="mailto:PHSInstAffairs@ucdavis.edu">Advising Team</a></p>
<h2>Graduate Program</h2>
<p>The UC Davis M.P.H. program’s mission is to develop a diverse and capable public health workforce and public health leaders of the future by providing a high-quality master’s degree curriculum in partnership with professional and academic public health educators and with real-world learning in the community.</p>
<p>We accomplish our mission through the collaborative efforts of the UC Davis and health networks, including the Schools of Medicine, Veterinary Medicine, Management, Law, Education, and Nursing and the California Department of Public Health, local county health departments, and non-profit agencies. These partnerships comprise teaching, student mentorship and practicum placements, research, service, direction, and support for the UC Davis M.P.H. Program.</p>
<p>The UC Davis M.P.H. Program is an accelerated, in-person, 56-unit program that focuses on the essentials of public health.  It offers students two concentration areas—General Public Health and Epidemiology—and includes a practicum experience in a public health setting. The program is accredited by Council of Education on Public Health (CEPH). The program is <em>not </em>STEM designated.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/mmph">Public Health (MPH)</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The MPH program is designed to develop the public health leaders of the future by providing a Council on Education for Public Health accredited high-quality curriculum in partnership with the public health community. The MPH program is a collaborative educational effort of the UC Davis and health networks, including the Schools of Medicine, Veterinary Medicine, Management, Law, Education, and Nursing and the California Department of Public Health, local county health departments, and non-profit agencies. </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

