<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Maternal &amp; Child Nutrition, Master of Advanced Study</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://nutrition.ucdavis.edu/academics/grad-programs/mcn" target="_blank">Master of Advanced Study in Maternal &amp; Child Nutrition</a>; <a href="https://nutrition.ucdavis.edu/academics/grad-programs/mcn/faculty" target="_blank">Faculty</a></p>
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Department of Nutrition offers the degree of M.A.S. in Maternal &amp; Child Nutrition. The program consists of four required core courses (22 units), special topics seminars (4 units), elective (4 units) and a six-unit student capstone for a total of 36 units.</p>
<p>Each student will be assigned a guidance committee consisting of two members to advise the student in completing a student capstone project.</p>
<p>The program includes an option for students to complete the lactation-specific didactic education required to take the exam to be an International Board-Certified Lactation Consultant. Eligible students may have the option of enrolling in 2 additional units of clinical lactation internship during the summer between years 1 and 2 of the program<span class="acronym">.</span></p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>Admission to the program requires a bachelor's degree with prior course work that includes (or is comparable to): one year of general chemistry, two quarters (one semester) of organic chemistry, a course in statistics, one course in general physiology, and two quarters (one semester) of the biochemistry of nutrition.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gmcn">Maternal &amp; Child Nutrition</a>.</p>
<h3>Courses</h3>
<p>See courses under <a href="/courses-subject-code/mcn/">Maternal &amp; Child Nutrition (MCN)</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The UC Davis Master of Advanced Study in Maternal and Child Nutrition Program is designed to provide a strong scientific background in maternal and child health topics, and to train professionals to design, implement, and evaluate nutrition intervention programs for mothers and children from a wide variety of cultural, ethnic, and social backgrounds.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

