<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Business Administration Online, Master of Business Administration Online</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<pre>H. Rao Unnava, Ph.D., Dean
</pre>
<p>Hemant Bhargava, Ph.D., Associate Dean<br/>
Joseph Chen, Ph.D., Program Chair</p>
<h2>School Office</h2>
<p>Gallagher Hall; 530-752-7658; <a href="https://gsm.ucdavis.edu/online-mba" target="_blank">Graduate School of Management</a>; <a href="https://gsm.ucdavis.edu/faculty-and-research/faculty-directory?glossary_filter=All&amp;search=" target="_blank">Faculty</a></p>
<h2>Program of Study</h2>
<p>Offering first-of-its-kind access to a nationally ranked University of California management school, MBA@UCDavis provides a top-quality, transformational experience—your opportunity to earn a UC Davis graduate business degree from anywhere in the world.</p>
<p>Through a close-knit online community and in-person residential experiences, we empower you to collaborate with a group of diverse, highly motivated, caring professionals who will challenge you to be your best.</p>
<p>We’ll connect you with our global alumni network and corporate partners across Northern California. You'll benefit from the strong relationships we’ve built in Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>The centerpiece of the MBA@UCDavis online experience is the live online classes where you will participate in spirited, face-to-face conversations with your peers and our world-class faculty through our state-of-the-art technology platform.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/smbo">Business Administration - Online</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The UC Davis MBA program merges teaching excellence, pioneering research and a collaborative leadership program to prepare globally aware, agile leaders who are committed to making a positive impact on the world. the school offers a Full-time MBA program in Davis, and Part-Time MBA programs in Sacramento and the San Francisco Bay Area—and now virtually in an Online MBA program.  </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

