<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Business Administration, Master of Business Administration</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<pre>H. Rao Unnava, Ph.D., Dean
</pre>
<pre>Hemant Bhargava Ph.D., Associate Dean</pre>
<pre>Joseph Chen, Ph.D., Program Chair</pre>
<h2>School Office</h2>
<p>Gallagher Hall; 530-752-7658; <a href="http://gsm.ucdavis.edu/" target="_blank">Graduate School of Management</a>; <a href="https://gsm.ucdavis.edu/faculty-and-research/faculty-directory?glossary_filter=All&amp;search=" target="_blank">Faculty</a></p>
<h2>Program of Study</h2>
<p>The hallmark of the UC Davis Master of Business Administration (MBA) program is its flexibility. Our STEM-designated program reflects UC Davis' nationally recognized leadership in the STEM fields. Our rigorous curriculum emphasizes quantitative analysis and data-driven decision-making, which will prepare you for leadership roles in STEM fields. Innovative application of data in business decision-making has become a highly valued skill demanded by employers—especially here in Northern California and Silicon Valley.  <br/>
 <br/>
The required core curriculum is designed to provide students foundation in the functional areas of business- accounting, economics, finance, marketing, organizational behavior, statistics, and strategy. These management disciplines are examined through the use of case studies, lectures and the analysis of a few select companies on which to base illustrations and spark discussions. As early as the first year of study, students are able to integrate elective courses into their personal curriculum.<br/>
 <br/>
Elective courses at the Graduate School of Management place an emphasis on real-world application of management principles through the use of executive guest speakers who present “live” case study analyses and actual “client” businesses for student projects. Many courses require team projects and emphasize managing by innovation and entrepreneurial thinking. These team projects develop your independent research abilities and hone your presentation skills. With a wide variety of electives offered every year, students can build their own MBA curriculum based on their goals. </p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/smba">Business Administration (MBA)</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The UC Davis MBA program merges teaching excellence, pioneering research and a collaborative leadership program to prepare globally aware, agile leaders who are committed to making a positive impact on the world. the school offers a Full-time MBA program in Davis, and Part-Time MBA programs in Sacramento and the San Francisco Bay Area—and now virtually in an Online MBA program.  </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

