<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Nursing Science &amp; Health-Care Leadership, Doctor of Philosophy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p>Sheryl L. Catz, Ph.D., Doctor of Philosophy Degree Program Director</p>
<h2>Nursing Science &amp; Health-Care Leadership Graduate Degree Program; Doctor of Philosophy Degree Program </h2>
<p>The Nursing Science and Health-Care Leadership Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) Degree Program at UC Davis prepares graduates as leaders in health care, health policy and education and research at the university level to conduct transformative research, educate health professionals and researchers, effect system change, influence and implement policy, and advance health from multiple settings. Through this four-year program, students work closely with their academic advisors to complete core courses and select personally tailored cognates, methods and other elective courses that support their dissertation research and education goals. Graduates will develop leadership skills that allow them to evaluate and integrate interdisciplinary perspectives, conduct transformative research and incorporate innovative technology.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gnsl">Nursing Science-Health-Care Leadership (Ph.D.)</a>.</p>
<h3>Faculty</h3>
<p>The UC Davis Nursing Science and Health-Care Leadership Graduate Group includes a wide cross-section of academic disciplines with faculty from the Betty Irene Moore School of Nursing as well as UC Davis Health and other UC Davis schools, colleges, and departments. Within the graduate group faculty are experts in nursing, medicine, health informatics, nutrition, pharmacy, biostatistics, public health and various clinical specialties.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Doctor of Philosophy program prepares graduates as health-care and health policy leaders as well as nurse faculty and researchers at the university level. Ideal students want to focus on important societal health issues through the work of advancing health and improving the systems that provide health services.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

