<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Performance Studies, Doctor of Philosophy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Ph.D. in Performance Studies is a four-year program. In the first two years of study, students develop an understanding of performance by drawing from a range of regular course offerings in the field to identify, explore, and define a field or fields of research. Students are required to complete four core courses out of five in performance studies, and one colloquium course. Each individual program is then built from seminar and/or practice as research courses, as well as independent or group studies, developing one or more of the four strands of the program: Comparative Medias, Embodiments, Cultures/Ecologies, and History/Text. A wide range of affiliated faculty offer courses throughout the HArCS faculty, and Designated Emphases are available in Studies in Performance &amp; Practice, African American &amp; African Studies, Critical Theory, Feminist Theory &amp; Research, Native American Studies, Religious Studies, Science &amp; Technology Studies, and Writing, Rhetoric &amp; Composition Studies. Students are required to complete a minimum of 60 units before taking the qualifying examination. No more than 12 units may be taken below the graduate level unless specifically approved by the Ph.D. graduate program advisor.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gpfs">Performance Studies</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>Composed of four clusters of interest;  interactive medias, cultures/ecologies, text/history, and embodiments. The Performance Studies program engages students in ways of thinking about performance that are historically, politically, culturally, and rhetorically informed. This interdisciplinary program encourages students to develop original dissertation research that explores and questions the artistic, social, and political ramifications of performance and the performative.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

