<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Statistics, Master of Science</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p>Jiming Jiang, Ph.D., Chairperson of the Program<br/>
Jie Peng, Ph.D., Vice Chairperson for Graduate Affairs</p>
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Graduate Program in Statistics offers programs of study and research leading to M.S. and Ph.D. degrees. The M.S. gives students a strong foundation in the theory of statistics as well as substantial familiarity with the most widely used statistical methods. Facility in computer programming is essential for some of the course work. The supervised statistical consulting required of all M.S. students has proven to be a valuable educational experience. The Ph.D. program combines advanced course work in statistics and probability with the opportunity for in-depth concurrent study in an applied field. For detailed information contact the Chairperson of the Program or the Graduate Advisor.</p>
<p><strong>Standard Track. </strong>32 units of core coursework and 12 units of electives are required for a total of 44 units.</p>
<p><strong>Emphasis in Data Science Track. </strong>32 units of core coursework and 16 units of electives are required for a total of 48 units.</p>
<p><a href="https://statistics.ucdavis.edu/grad/admissions">Admissions Information</a>; <a href="https://statistics.ucdavis.edu/grad/ms">Program Information</a></p>
<h3>Preparation</h3>
<p>Preparation for the graduate program requires a year of calculus, a course in linear algebra, facility with a programming language and upper division coursework in mathematics and/or statistics.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gsta">Statistics</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Statistics graduate M.S. program provides students with broad familiarity with the most widely used statistical methods and with solid background in statistical computing. Students acquire a solid background in probability and mathematical statistics and are trained in modern statistical methods, data analysis, applications, and computational tools. </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

