<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Integrated Teaching Credential, Teaching Credential, Master of Arts</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<p>Cynthia Passmore, Ph.D., Interim Program Chair<br/>
​Cynthia Passmore, Ph.D., Graduate Advisor<br/>
Janelle Barnes, Graduate Coordinator</p>
<p>School of Education Building; 530-752-5887; <a href="mailto:eduadvising@ucdavis.edu">Advising</a>; <a href="https://education.ucdavis.edu/faculty-directory" target="_blank">Faculty</a></p>
<p>The Teaching Credential with Master's Degree Program offers an opportunity for qualified students to complete the requirements for both a Masters of Arts in Education degree and a Multiple Subject or Single Subject Credential in English, mathematics, science, social science or agriculture in a six-quarter program completed in less than two years. A Bilingual authorization in Spanish or Mandarin, is available to credential candidates in multiple subjects or the single subjects of English, mathematics, science or social science.</p>
<p>The Credential Program prepares students for the teaching profession by immersing them in the total environment of a public school classroom while enrolled in required coursework. The coursework incorporates a theoretical practical approach to the teaching-learning process, encouraging close interactions among teacher candidates and teacher education faculty. Students complete requirements for the M.A. degree during two part-time quarters following the credential year. This coursework introduces the integration of research into teaching practice, making teachers more informed and pro-active practitioners.</p>
<h2>Teaching Credential/M.A. Degree Program</h2>
<p>Applicants are encouraged to have program prerequisites and testing requirements completed prior to submitting an application. Credential requirements are regularly revised by the State of California. To obtain the most current information, students considering a career in teaching are encouraged to see <a href="https://education.ucdavis.edu/credentialma" target="_blank">Credential/MA</a> and consult with the School of Education advisors throughout their undergraduate career.</p>
<h2>M.A. in Education Degree Programs</h2>
<p>Applicants to the General Track M.A. must have completed an undergraduate degree with a major in a field that supports their intended area of emphasis. A minimum undergraduate GPA of 3.000 is necessary for graduate admission at the University of California, Davis. Please consult with advisors in the School of Education regarding additional testing or supplemental information that may be required for application to a specific program.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gemc">Education (Credential/M.A.)</a>.</p>
<h3>Courses</h3>
<p>See <a href="/courses-subject-code/edu/">Education (EDU)</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The School of Education offers a combined program to earn a teaching credential and a Master of Arts degree. The program prepares elementary and secondary teachers and is designed to immerse students in the total environment of the classroom, provide a theoretical-practical approach to the teaching-learning process, and encourage close interaction between faculty and students. </p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

