<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Transportation Technology &amp; Policy, Doctor of Philosophy</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<informationtext name="Information">
<![CDATA[
<h2>Graduate Study</h2>
<p>The Graduate Group in Transportation Technology &amp; Policy offers the M.S. (Plan I—thesis; and Plan II—exam), and Ph.D. degrees. Students complete three core courses in technology, policy, and data science and choose one of three tracks: Vehicles &amp; Fuels, Demand &amp; Behavior or Infrastructure &amp; Operations. The curriculum draws on multiple disciplines including civil, mechanical, and environmental engineering, economics, statistics, political science, psychology, sociology, geography, and urban planning.</p>
<p><span style="color:rgb(0, 0, 0)">M.S. students complete three core courses, two track courses, two skills courses plus electives. Ph.D. students take the same plus an additional skill course and additional electives. Master's degrees require a minimum of 36 quarter units and doctoral degrees require a minimum of 54 units. M.S. Plan I students may replace up to 6 units of regular course work with research (course 299) units. At least two thirds of all credits must be at the graduate level.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-family: proxima-nova, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Ubuntu, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, sans-serif, &quot;Apple Color Emoji&quot;, &quot;Segoe UI Emoji&quot;, &quot;Segoe UI Symbol&quot;;">Preparation</h3>
<p style="font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; font-size: 19.5239px; font-family: proxima-nova, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Ubuntu, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, sans-serif, &quot;Apple Color Emoji&quot;, &quot;Segoe UI Emoji&quot;, &quot;Segoe UI Symbol&quot;;">Applicants will normally be expected to have completed two courses in calculus and one course each in calculus level statistics and microeconomics.</p>
<h3>Degree Requirements &amp; Program Coordinator</h3>
<p>See <a href="https://grad.ucdavis.edu/programs/gttp">Transportation Technology &amp; Policy</a>.</p>
]]>
</informationtext>
<quickviewtext name="Quick View">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Transportation Technology and Policy program is designed to meet the world’s growing need for highly qualified, thoughtful, and dedicated leaders in sustainable transportation. Students complete three core courses in Transportation Technology, Transportation Policy, and Data Science and choose one of three tracks in which to specialize: Vehicles &amp; Fuels, Demand &amp; Behavior, or Infrastructure &amp; Operations.</p>
]]>
</quickviewtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

